<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://apply-templates.com/templates/main.xsl"?>
<at:post xmlns:xh="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:at="https://apply-templates.com"
         postid="7"
         posturl="posts/7.xml">
    <at:title>My knowledge of DTD's is a little Rusty...</at:title>
    <at:author>Daniel</at:author>
    <at:date>2022-03-09</at:date>
    <at:content>
        <xh:p>Hello all! I hope life has been treating you well.</xh:p>
        <xh:p>I have started learning Rust! I'm working through the books for it which have been all great so far, and honestly, the borrow checker and type system are really well thought out; I cannot see myself going back to python again for anything except small scripts. One of the things that I have noticed is somewhat lackluster is the XML support, which for a language that seems from the ground up to be based on the idea of "don't cut corners, work on it and get it right first time round" is perplexing, XML and its benefits seem to be exactly what the Rust community should want.</xh:p>
        <xh:p>Of course, the fix for this is to implement the tooling that they need, so I am dipping my toes in with a project called <xh:a href="https://github.com/ballsteve/xrust">xrust</xh:a>, which intends to build a complete XSLT 3 processor! I am currently focusing on the XML parsing parts of the library (and if you'd like to help on any aspect of the project, please reach out on the github page!), but the big challenge in front of me is DTDs, which I have started into implementing in earnest. The XML conformance test suite appears to have a dizzying array of tests for which, once we pass, I am very confident we'll be fully in compliance, however I would like to get some more tests if possible.</xh:p>
        <xh:p>If you have samples of the most rancid, crime-against-god-and-nature DTDs and the XML they work with that you could send me, I'd appreciate it. You can email me at the link at the top of the page or DM me on Github or Twitter. So far I have found an <xh:a href="http://www.詹姆斯.com/blog/2007/10/obfuscated-atom">amazing example</xh:a> that has the DTD expand out to form an entire atom feed, but was wondering if there is anything else out there I could look at.</xh:p>
    </at:content>
</at:post>
